Spas Zdravkov Spasov

AL

Sofia, Bulgaria

6

00359 (0)888 989 764

~

spas.z.spasov@gmail.com

github.com/metalevel-tech

(3)

askubuntu.com/users/566421



Year of birth 1980, single

Resume

Computers and computer science in general have been my hobby since I was eight years old. In 2021 I decided to follow my dream and turn this hobby into a new professional career. I left my previous job as a management consultant, shortly after I applied to some courses to improve my skills in the area of IT.

Since then, I've completed a few JavaScript courses and finished few small freelance projects. At the beginning of 2023 I started my first job as a software developer with TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, etc. My interests at this moment are in the direction of full stack development. In my free time, when I'm not playing with computers, I like reading books, hiking & gym training.

My belief is that the world grows through sharing knowledge between individuals. What I am looking for is the opportunity to focus my efforts in the right direction, to learn new things and the challenge to solve tasks that are beyond my current knowledge.

Education

2010 – 2015 **Doctor of Engineering Science in Automated Systems for Data Processing and Management**Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, Department of Automation of Discrete Production Engineering.

2005 – 2007 Master of Science in Computer Technologies in Mechanical Engineering
Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Machine Technology, Department of Technology of
Machine Building and Metal Cutting Machines.

2001 – 2005 Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering
 Technical University of Sofia, Faculty of Machine Technology, Department of Technology of Machine Building and Metal Cutting Machines.

 $2000-2001 \quad \text{Army service in Special Forces of Bulgarian Army, Paratrooper}.$

1995 – 1999 Specialist Degree
 High School of Machine Technologies, Pazardjik, Bulgaria,
 Department of Machine-Building.

Languages

Bulgarian Native

English Conversational



This CV as web page at https://metalevel.tech

Employment History

2023 – now Software Developer at "Browserbite OOD".

Sofia, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Development of web applications with JavaScript related technologies.

One of the best teams I've ever worked with. Nice company where I got the opportunity to start my actual IT career.

Regrettably, due to a lack of new client acquisitions in recent months, the company has had to make the difficult decision to release all members of its staff from their roles.

2021 - 2023 Career Break.

Sofia, Bulgaria Activities: Accomplish few JavaScript courses. Done few freelance tasks related to web (mainly

frontend) development and Linux server administration.

2019 – 2021 Management consultant, IT administrator and specialist at "Information Technologies and

Sofia, Bulgaria the Future of the Economic Science Foundation".

Positions and activities: Development of training programs and presentations of the company; Executive of trainings of the personal of the company; Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Project management; System administrator of the IT infrastructure of the company and support its Internet presence.

2017 – 2019 Management consultant at "Engineering Culture in the Management of the Future

Sofia, Bulgaria Foundation".

Positions and activities: Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Development of presentations of the company, acquiring new investors; Project management; System administrator of the IT infrastructure of the company.

2011 – 2017 Management consultant at "Trivium AD".

Yambol, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Consultant of ERP/PLM systems and industrial enterprise management; Project management; Development of training programs and executive of trainings of the personal of the customers.

2007 – 2011 Production engineer and technologist, at "Hydraulic Elements and Systems AD".

Yambol, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Production engineer, team leader, project manager, chief technologist of the metal-cutting processes with CNC machines.

2006 – 2007 Technologist at "Teximp S.A. branch Bulgaria".

Sofia, Bulgaria Positions and activities: Technologist, technical consultant, warehouse manager; service team coordinator.

2004 – 2006 Associate in the Laboratory of Mechanical Engineering Technology, at "Technical University *Sofia, Bulgaria* of Sofia".

Experience relevant to the position

In the last months at Browserbite, I was working with TypeScript, Next.js, React.js and Material-UI and developed an application for "application cost estimations" for the company's projects - https://appstimate.io/

Along with my work tasks, for the past few months, I've been continuing to learn TypeScript, Next.js and React and mastering Git in details.

Another interesting fact about me and Browserbite was that as an entry assignment they challenged me to lean TypeScript and few (new to me) React.js conceptions for a week – here is the result: https://swapi.metalevel.tech/

Along with JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML and CSS I'm having a degree of experience with:

- PHP: Basic level, creating plugins for WordPress and MediaWiki, hobby Laravel projects.
- SQL: Basic level, administration of MySQL and MariaDB databases simple queries, etc.
- Python: Basic level, solving some hobby tasks.
- Lua: Basic level, creating modules for MediaWiki.

More relevant IT experience

From 2015 to 2021 I have been undertaking the job of a system administrator for my former employers. This required me to learn how to setup and maintain Linux server; deploy and manage different CMS as MediaWiki and WordPress and all related services – as webservers, firewalls, databases, etc.; setup and manage Microsoft 365 for a small organization.

I've been using ProxmoxVE for the past four years as a bare metal hypervisor solution in my home laboratory. I also have extensive experience with cloud providers such as DigitalOcean, Linode.

Currently, in my hobby projects, I'm really enjoying the amazing features which offers the online services as CloudFlare, Vercel, MongoDB, GitHub and GitLab and more.

I'm good at shell scripting, like to automate the things make them robust as possible and even creates own backup solutions when it is needed.

I like GNU/Linux much, primary using Debian and Debian based distributions and have in touch with user management, deployment, maintenance, and optimization of services such as Apache2, NginX, MariaDB, MySQL, PHP-FPM, MediaWiki, NextCloud, OnlyOffice, WordPress, Apache Guacamole, Redis, Elasticsearch, Iptables, Ipset, Postfix, Docker, Linux containers, virtual machines, and others.